### Contact

(+351) 925 238 478 (Home) campos.monteiro@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/fernandocampos-monteiro-18209217 (LinkedIn)

www.pulsar-development.com/ pessoas/ (Company)

## Top Skills

Banking

Financial Risk

Risk Management

## Languages

French (Elementary)

English (Professional Working)

Portuguese (Native or Bilingual)

### **Publications**

FACTORING: PRUDENTIAL AND MARKET CONDUCT REGULATIONS

LEASING AND FACTORING

LEASING AND FACTORING
- ANALYSIS OF ANGOLAN
LEGISLATIVE FRAMEWORK AND
DRAFT REGULATIONS

Barómetro Banca

# Fernando Campos Monteiro

**Economist** 

Lisbon

# Summary

A I'm a finance professional with a recognized accounting qualification with more than 30 years of experience in Banking and Corporations. A motivated, entrepreneurial mindset, high energy and the ability to work in a fast moving environment.

Excellent presentation skills, a hands-on attitude combined with a willingness to immerse in detail.

Experience in delivering management information, improving processes and shaping the agenda for business and financial planning. Exhibit a positive attitude represent the company in a highly professional manner to clients & partners.

Managing and prioritizing tasks efficiently and effectively.

# Experience

PULSAR Consulting Group GmbH Associate Partner September 2019 - Present (1 year 1 month) London, Londres, UK

Company Description - Is a leading business development consultancy, with regional head offices in London, Luanda, Lima and Hong Kong. We support our clients in international infrastructure projects and intercontinental business development activities. Our operations are centered on rapid growth of new business opportunities, and we assist companies in entering or expanding into markets throughout Africa, Asia, South America and Europe. PDI's customer promise is built on three core pillars: experience, engagement, and profitability.

- Business Model and Strategic Planning for Commercial Bank in Angola
- Business Model and Strategic Planning for Commercial Bank in Cabo Verde
- Business Model and Strategic Planning for Development Bank in Angola
- Business Model and Strategic Planning for Reinsurance Corporation in Angola

• Business Model and Strategic Planning for Credit Rating Agency in Angola

#### Banco BCS

Head of Finance

September 2016 - September 2019 (3 years 1 month)

Company Description - Banco BCS – It's a Private and Corporate Bank establish in Angola since 2015.

- Start-up Bank operations.
- Implementation of financial and risk policies.
- 15th Ranking in 28 banks after 3 years.

### Banco Kwanza Invest SA

CFO - CRO

September 2013 - September 2016 (3 years 1 month)

Angola

Company Description - Advisory counsels private investors, corporations and institutional clients on direct private investments to private companies

- Managing and overseeing the cash flow of the Bank and ensuring it has the appropriate treasury controls.
- Managing hedging and foreign currencies; managing relationships with Investors;
- Managing and overseeing the company's financial systems

### Goldman

Country Manager

December 2011 - July 2013 (1 year 8 months)

Company Description - By offering financial institutions the breadth of solutions, thought leadership needed to successfully manage risk and achieve superior returns on their investment, Goldman will become the premier trusted advisor to the banking industry.

- Portuguese local public administration reform,
- IPSAS International Public Sector Accounting Standards

Banco de Poupança e Crédito

Advisor To The Board

October 2006 - December 2011 (5 years 3 months)

Luanda, Angola

Company Description - Banco BPC is the country's largest commercial bank, having branches in every province of Angola. 1956 - 1975: Banco Comercial

de Angola 1975 - 1991: Banco Popular de Angola 1991 - 2004: Banco de Poupança e Crédito

- Providing sound financial support and insights to enable the Board to make critical business decisions.
- Play a key role in the formulation of the business's strategy.
- Advising on market changes and providing strategic financial recommendations to the Board.
- Revenue assurance program that resulted in a revenue increase of USD 197.000.000 in 2010.

Movicel Telecomunications
Head Of Finance
August 2003 - September 2006 (3 years 2 months)
Angola

Company Description - Present in the Angolan market since 2003, Movicel was the first company to offer advantages and benefits from telecommunication in the country. The company started its activities in 1997, still as part of Angola Telecom, the government telecom operator, managing the starting number 91 mobile network.

- Providing sound financial support and insights to enable the Board to make critical business decisions.
- Presentation of financial results and insights to the Board.
- Managing and overseeing the taxation affairs of the organization and liaising with the external tax firm for specialist advice.

Marks and Spencer 12 years 10 months

Head of Finance

January 2002 - July 2003 (1 year 7 months)

Lisboa, Lisboa, Portugal

Company Description - Marks and Spencer Group plc (commonly abbreviated as M&S or colloquially Marks and Sparks) is a major British multinational retailer with headquarters in London, England. It is listed on the London Stock Exchange and is a constituent of the FTSE 250 Index.

 Managing and tracking budget and accounting information including billing, collections, and tax information;

- Overseeing commercial decision making from tender analysis, margin analysis, pricing analysis etc.
- Overseeing Accounts Payable, Accounts Receivable, Tax, Treasury, Payroll,
   Financial and Management Accounting functions.

Deputy Head of Finance October 1996 - February 2002 (5 years 5 months)

Head Of Accounting
October 1990 - October 1996 (6 years 1 month)

C&L (PWC)

Auditor

July 1988 - July 1989 (1 year 1 month)

Reliability of financial and management reporting. Regulatory roles

# Education

ISEG - Lisbon School of Economics & Management Master of Science (MSc), Economics · (1992 - 1996)

**ISGB** 

Master's degree, Banking and Finance (2003 - 2005)

Instituto Superior de Contabilidade e Administração de Lisboa - ISCAL

BS, Accounting · (1985 - 1988)